whitepages.co.uk 2014-06-26

# Privacy and Cookie Policy

**Privacy Policy**

Peopletracer Ltd ("We") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our [terms of use](http://www.whitepages.co.uk/about-whitepages/website-terms-of-use.html) and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the **Act** ), the data controller is Peopletracer Ltd of Global Reach, Dunleavy Drive, Cardiff, CF11 0SN. 

We are registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office under registration number Z1898545.

#### 1. INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

1.1 We may collect and process the following data about you: -

1.1.1 Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site [www.whitepages.co.uk](http://www.whitepages.co.uk/) ( **our site** ). This includes information provided at the time of posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our site.

1.1.2 If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

1.1.3 We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

1.1.4 Details of transactions you carry out through our site.

1.1.5 Details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access. 

#### _2. COOKIES AND IP ADDRESSES_

2.1 We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type for system administration and functionality, and your general internet usage, by using Cookies. These are files that contain information that is transferred to and stored on your computer or mobile device. Cookies enable us to operate our Website effectively and deliver a better and more personalised service to our Users. Our Cookies are not used to collect personally identifiable information about you.

2.2 Types of Cookies

We categorise below the types of Cookies that we use, together with a brief description of what they are used for. This list is not exhaustive:

Strictly Necessary

Strictly necessary Cookies are essential to enable you to receive a Service on our Website. This includes for example, Cookies enabling you to log into the Website so that we can authenticate your access to your Account and purchase Services and so as to comply with the law (e.g. to help keep your visit to the Website secure). They also enable us to provide help facilities such as “Live Chat”. We would not be able to operate our Website without using such strictly necessary Cookies.

Functionality

Functionality Cookies allow the Website to store information about your preferences when you return, so as to allow us to customise our Website according to your individual interests. They also allow us to note your browser’s capabilities so that everyone’s browsing is as responsive as possible and by measuring any errors that occur so that they can be resolved swiftly.

Performance

Performance Cookies collect information about how you may use our Website, for instance to estimate our audience size and usage pattern. This includes website analytics Cookies such as those provided by [Google.com](http://google.com/).

Social Network Sharing

Where you elect to share online content through social networks like Facebook and Twitter, these Companies may set third party Cookies on your device. Some parts of our Website may also use AddThis to provide sharing features. Their Privacy Policies can be accessed as follows:

2.3 By using our site you are deemed to accept the Website Terms of Use incorporating this Privacy and Cookies Policy and consent to our use of Cookies. You may withdraw this consent by activating the settings on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of Cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser’s settings so that it will refuse Cookies, our system will issue Cookies when you log on to our Website. You can find out how to do this for your particular browser by clicking “help” on your browser's menu, or by visiting: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). For information about how to delete cookies from your mobile phone, tablet or other handheld device you will need to refer to the “help” function or relevant operating manual.

#### 

#### 

#### 3. WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

3.1 The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us, for one of our affiliates or one of our contracting partners. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the supply of your service, and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. 

3.2 All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. ****

3.3 Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access and to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information under our control.

#### 4. USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

4.1 We use information held about you in the following ways: -

4.1.1 To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 

4.1.2 To efficiently provide you with relevant information, and or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. 

4.1.3 To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.

4.1.4 To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.

4.1.5 To notify you about changes to our service, new features or other offers that we can provide.

4.2 We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by [post or telephone]. 

4.3 If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this.

4.4 If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or if you do not wish us to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please send an email to [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'mailto:';%20var%20suffix%20=%20'';%20var%20attribs%20=%20'';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy16540%20=%20'info'%20+%20'@';%20addy16540%20=%20addy16540%20+%20'peopletracer'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'co'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'uk';%20document.write\(%20'%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20addy16540%20+%20suffix%20+%20'\\''%20+%20attribs%20+%20'%3E'%20\);%20document.write\(%20addy16540%20\);%20document.write\(%20'%3C\\/a%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20e-mail%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3C/'%20\);%20document.write\(%20'span%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E)[info@peopletracer.co.uk](mailto:info@peopletracer.co.uk).

4.5 We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to advertisers.

#### 5. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

5.1 We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the Companies Act 2006.

5.2 We may disclose your personal information to third parties: - 

5.2.1 In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

5.2.2 If Peopletracer Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

5.2.3 If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce, apply or fulfill our [terms of use](http://www.whitepages.co.uk/about-whitepages/website-terms-of-use.html) and our obligations under other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Peopletracer Limited, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection credit referencing, debt collecting and tracing.

#### **6. YOUR RIGHTS**

6.1 You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any by sending an email to [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'mailto:';%20var%20suffix%20=%20'';%20var%20attribs%20=%20'';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy58069%20=%20'info'%20+%20'@';%20addy58069%20=%20addy58069%20+%20'peopletracer'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'co'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'uk';%20document.write\(%20'%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20addy58069%20+%20suffix%20+%20'\\''%20+%20attribs%20+%20'%3E'%20\);%20document.write\(%20addy58069%20\);%20document.write\(%20'%3C\\/a%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20e-mail%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3C/'%20\);%20document.write\(%20'span%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E)[info@peopletracer.co.uk](mailto:info@peopletracer.co.uk).

6.2 Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

#### **7. ACCESS TO INFORMATION**

The Data Protection Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

#### **8. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

#### **9. CONTACT**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to Customer Services, Peopletracer Ltd Global Reach, Dunleavy Drive, Cardiff CF11 0SN. Alternatively please email [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'mailto:';%20var%20suffix%20=%20'';%20var%20attribs%20=%20'';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy50834%20=%20'info'%20+%20'@';%20addy50834%20=%20addy50834%20+%20'peopletracer'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'co'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'uk';%20document.write\(%20'%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20addy50834%20+%20suffix%20+%20'\\''%20+%20attribs%20+%20'%3E'%20\);%20document.write\(%20addy50834%20\);%20document.write\(%20'%3C\\/a%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20e-mail%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3C/'%20\);%20document.write\(%20'span%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E)[info@peopletracer.co.uk](mailto:info@peopletracer.co.uk) or call 029 2067 8567.

---
